《法外情真》前情回顾
Previously on The Guardian
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我不想结婚只是因为我怀孕了
I don't want get married just because I'm pregnant.
我已经做好当爸爸的准备了
I know that I'm ready to be a father.
我动脉堵塞了
I've got a little blockage,
五条里面四条都堵了
four out of five arterial.
那你要做手术了吗
So you'll need surgery?
可以给我一杯龙舌兰酒吗
Can I have a shot of Tequila?
我就和其他人一样喜欢做爱
I like sex as anybody like sex.
你不能再酗酒了  尼古拉斯
You can't drink anymore Nicolas.
你不能再吸毒了
You can't use drugs.
而且你不能再撒谎了
And you can not continue to lie...
对你爱的那些人
to the people who love you.
露露  我跟你求婚了  可你却看着我好像我在侮辱你
Lulu I asked you to marry me and you just looked at me like I was insulting you.
你可以告诉法庭
You can just tell the court...
我是个瘾君子  呃
that I'm some addicts... uh...
缓刑犯
some probationer...
你可以就带着孩子离开
You can take the child and you can just go.
这就是你跟苏珊娜·佩尔上床的原因吗？
So you screw Suzanne Pell?
尼克
Nick.
你真的要这样吗
You're really gonna do this?
- 尼克  - 求你了  露露
- Nick... - Lulu, please.
别走
Don't go.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
嗨
Hey.
外面真的是太冷了
lt's cold as hell out there.
这应该会持续一周
lt's supposed to last all week.
嗯
Right.
你吃过饭了吗
Have you eaten?
我不饿
I'm fine.
我在外面碰到露露了
I saw Lulu outside.
嗯
Yeah.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about that.
嗯
Yeah.
这样也许对大家都好
Probably all for the best.
什么
What?
她也许做得没错  暂时
She's probably doing the right thing... for now.
听着  我  呃
Listen, l, uh...
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
别这样
Oh, come on.
不  你听我说完  孩子
No. Hey, hear me out, son.
我给一些人打了几个电话  找到了这个地方
I made some calls, and I found this place and, uh...
这个是匿名的
lt's anonymous.
你可以去门诊看一看
You can do that outpatient thing.
爸  我不需要康复治疗
Dad, I don't need to go to some rehab--
儿子  你需要帮助
Son, you need help.
你得做出一些改变  否则你最后会坐牢的  或者更糟
You've gotta make some changes. You're gonna end up in jail... or worse.
我没事
I'm fine.
你能不能明天跟我一起去一趟  我们一起去看一看
Will you just go out there tomorrow with me and we'll take a look at the place?
明天吗  我们明天要谈雷诺公司合并的事
Tomorrow? We have the Renstar merger tomorrow.
我知道
I know.
我最近两个星期时间都花在那封意见信上了
I've been working for the last two weeks on that opinion letter.
那我们就结束这个案子  明天一起出去到这个地方看看
So we close the deal, we go out there tomorrow, take a look.
你  你
You--you...
好吧
Well...
我希望你能认真考虑下这件事
I really do wish you'd take this seriously.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
第三季  第十二集
法外真情
翻译   马丁   倪
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
早上好
Morning.
哦  伯顿
Oh, Burton!
嗨
Hey.
听着  雷诺通信公司的人
Listen, the gentlemen from Renstar Communications
已经在会议室了
are in the conference room.
- 尼克到了吗  - 还没有
- Nick here yet? - No, not yet.
没有他我们还不能开始
Well, we can't start without him.
好吧  那我先去跟他们谈一谈
Right. Well, I'll go talk to them.
好的  去吧
Yeah, do that.
各位
Gentlemen.
你好
Hi.
露露  早上好
Morning, Lulu.
发生什么事了吗
ls something wrong?
找我有事吗  苏珊娜
What is it, Suzanne?
有个叫安妮塔·亨德里克斯的女人在你的办公室
There's a woman in your office. Her name is Anita Hendricks.
- 我不认识  - 她是尼克的客户
- I don't know her. - She's Nick's client.
那她待在我的办公室干什么
What is she doing in my office?
半年前她被夺走了她两岁大的孩子的监护权
Her two-year-old was removed from her custody six months ago.
她本来应该今天就能要回孩子的
She was supposed to get her back today.
本应该
Supposed to?
尼克没有出席法庭
Nick never showed up in court.
好吧
Fine!
早上好
Good morning.
我做了所有他们让我做的事  所有的事
I did everything that was asked of me! Everything!
我清醒了  找到了工作  去上了课
I'm sober. I got a job. I took the classes.
跟辅导员谈了
Met with the counselors.
我是路易莎·阿切尔
I'm Louisa Archer--
我做了我该做的事  你听到了吗
I did what I was supposed to do! You hear me?
我的孩子本来应该就是在今天跟我回家的
And my baby was supposed to come home with me this very day!
我非常抱歉
I'm really sorry.
法官女士说我要等到下周才能在去法庭
And the judge lady says I can't go back there until next week.
好吧
Okay.
等一下
Hang on.
能不能帮我找一下安妮塔  安妮塔
Can somebody get me Anita...Anita...
亨德里克斯
Hendricks!
安妮塔·亨德里克斯的档案
Anita Hendricks' file, please?
好的  亨德里克斯小姐  我先看下你的档案
Okay, Miss Hendricks, I'm gonna go over your file,
下次开庭我会亲自去监督
and then I am going to personally oversee your next court appointment.
我得等一个星期吗
I gotta wait a whole week?
是的
Right.
亨德里克斯小姐
Miss Hendricks.
我不能再等了
I ain't waiting no more.
我今天就想把我的宝宝接回来  接不到她我就不走了
I want my baby back today, and I ain't Ieaving until I get her.
能不能帮我找找尼克·法林现在在哪儿
Would someone please track down Nick Fallin for me?
现在
Now!
伯顿  他还没到
Burton, he's still not here.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know that.
没有意见信我们不能结案
And we can't close this deal without that opinion letter.
不开玩笑
No kidding.
他们已经开始生气了
And they're starting to get pissed.
给我留言
Leave a message.
尼古拉斯  我们现在需要那封意见信
Nicholas, We need that letter... now!
你把我们搞得很难堪
You're making us look ridiculous.
我能帮你什么忙吗
May I help you?
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
你好
Hi.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
尼克  尼克·法林
Nick. Nick Fallin.
你好  尼克·法林
Hello, Nick Fallin.
你好
Hello.
我爸给了我你们的宣传册
My father gave me a pamphlet.
然后呢
Okay.
上面说  呃
It said, uh--
我见过我们的宣传册
I've seen our pamphlet.
他说我应该来这里
He said I should come here.
好的
Good.
他建议我来的
He suggested it.
好的
Good.
你想来这里吗
Do you want to be here?
嗯  我想来
Yes. Yeah, I think I do.
我这就叫她
Then I'll call her.
叫谁
Who?
你会喜欢安妮的  大家都喜欢安妮
You'll love Anne. Everybody does.
哪种毒品
Drug of choice?
可卡因
Cocaine.
你嗑了多久了
How long have you been using?
断断续续  有16年了
Om and on, 16 years.
你嗑了多少
How much have you been using?
不一定的
It varies.
有的时候我嗑一点点
Sometimes I sneak a line or two.
有的时候多一点
Sometimes a little more.
喝酒吗
Alcohol?
有的时候会  嗯
Yeah, sometimes. Yeah.
还有其他吗
Anything else?
有的时候有
Sometimes.
是什么样的东西
What type of substance?
有的时候会嗑一点特制毒品
Sometimes, you know... designer drugs.
呃  迷幻药吗
Uh, ecstasy?
致幻剂吗
Hallucinogens?
嗯
Yeah.
你之前有接受过治疗吗
Have you ever been in treatment before?
有过
Uh, yeah.
我去过法院指定的的门诊
Uh, I went through a court-ordered outpatient thing.
- 你现在是在缓刑期吗  - 是的
- You're on probation? - Yeah.
这是多久的事了
How long ago was that?
两年多一点
A little over two years.
你上次嗑药是什么时候
When was the last time you used?
今天早上
This morning.
你现在清醒吗
You're high right now?
清醒的  问题就在这儿
No. See, that's the thing.
昨晚我爸去我那儿把这个宣传册给了我
Last night, my father came around and brought this pamphlet,
他告诉我  呃
and he told me, uh...
他跟我说  我需要振作起来
Well, he told me that I should straighten myself out.
我没听明白
I don't follow.
相反  我出门了
I went out instead and, uh...
遇到一个人  买了点他的毒品
saw this guy, and he sold me some stuff.
他卖的是哪种
What did he call it?
美人  蓝色梦幻
Beautiful. Blue Mystic.
迷幻剂的一种
An hallucinogen.
你嗑了多少
How much did you take?
我不知道  大概60毫克吧
I don't know. 60 milligrams?
什么都没发生吗
And nothing happened?
我觉得我嗑的就是小苏打
I think it's just baking soda.
60毫克可不少了啊  尼克
60 milligrams is a huge dose, Nick.
到那时我觉得你今天能过来是很明智的
But I think you've made a very wise decision coming here.
我们可以帮助你
And I think we can help.
你怎么缴费
Method of payment?
- 我能用信用卡吗  - 可以
- Can I use a credit card? - Mm-hmm.
我得接下电话
I have to take that.
你好  乔普林医生
Hello, Dr. Joplin.
好的
Right.
好
我会的  我会给他们打电话  我马上就来
I will. I will call them and come in.
你还好吗
You all right?
我只是
I just...
I'm just...
抱歉失陪一下
Please excuse me.
苏珊娜
Suzanne.
我在尝试修补  尼克犯下的错
I'm attempting to, uh, fix Nick's mistake.
所以今天下午4点
So this afternoon at 4:OO,
我需要你把安妮塔的女儿带到法院
I need you to bring Anita's daughter to the courthouse.
我办不到
I can't make it.
这件事已经被重新安排了  所以
lt's already been rescheduled, so--
安妮塔·亨德里克斯是不是没去你的办公室扎营的  苏珊娜
You don't have Anita Hendricks camped out in your office, Suzanne.
- 好吧  - 嗯
- Right. - Right.
那就把你的事办完然后过去
So just clear your schedule and be there.
呃  伯顿  听着  雷诺的那帮人要等到结案才会走
Uh, Burton. Look, the Renstar guys won't Ieave until we close this deal.
他们倒闭的时间事明天  所以在明天12:01之前都会待在这里
Their drop-dead date's tomorrow, so they're gonna camp out here until 12:01 .
好的
Right.
亨利·莫斯已经有点待不住了
Henry Moss is kinda starting to lose it.
他威胁说如果我们再不结案  他就会提起失职的诉讼
He's threatening a malpractice suit if we don't close this deal.
可以理解
It figures.
所以  我只能给他们不停地倒咖啡
So, uh, there's only so much comee I can offer 'em.
好的  我待会儿进去拖住他们
Okay. I'll, uh--I'll go in there and stall 'em.
好的
Great.
杰克  你去尼克家看看  他到底在做什么
Oh, listen, Jake. Go by Nick's house. See what the hell he's doing.
好的
Got it.
你好
Hello there.
恐怕安妮要离开一会儿了
I'm afraid that Anne had to leave.
安妮跟我说你在考虑
She told me that you were considering it.
我想我下次再来吧
You know, I think I'll come back at another time.
- 哦  是吗  - 嗯  我会的
- Oh. - Yeah, I think I'll do that.
尼克  你在吗
Nick?
尼克
Nick!
- 你去几楼  - 请帮我按下去法律事务所
- What floor? - The legal clinic, please.
好像叫LSP律所
I think it's called LSP.
安妮啊  你来这里做什么
Anne? What are you doing here?
我得了癌症
I've got cancer.
非常抱歉
I'm sorry.
我儿子还不知道
My son doesn't know it yet.
我快要死了  我的儿子
I'm dying and my son...
我得给他找个住的地方
I've got to find a place for him to go.
我一年前被确诊
I was diagnosed a year ago.
做了手术  也做了化疗  病情得到了缓解
I had surgery, did chemo, and went into remission.
我是说  我之前病情缓解了
I mean, I was in remission.
我的儿子跟我住在一起
My son, he lives with me.
嗯
Right.
他爸爸是个不着家  只知道工作的混蛋
His dad is a workaholic prick.
哦
Okay.
我一个人照顾儿子
I have full custody.
他爸爸一个月有一个周末可以见他  但是也经常不来
His father gets one weekend a month, which he usually blows off.
- 嗯  - 这样也好
- Right. - Which is probably for the best.
他害怕他爸爸
His father scares him.
- 害怕爸爸  - 脾气很差  对他不好
- Scares him? - Bad temper, tough on him.
好吧
Right.
我不想把儿子交给他
I don't want to leave my son with my ex-husband.
- 你又其他亲戚吗  - 我妹妹说她可以照顾他
- Do you have any alternatives? - My sister said she'd take him.
- 你妹妹  - 是的  她很喜欢我儿子  她还很年轻
- Your sister? - Yeah. She loves him. She's very young.
- 多年轻  - 她今年26  她是个好人
- How young? - She's 26, but she's a good person.
好吧
Right.
你前夫有没有虐待或者冷落你的儿子
Has your ex-husband ever abused or neglected your son?
你怎么定义虐待
How do you measure abuse?
我想要签一个拒绝心肺复苏的预嘱
I'd like a ''Do Not Resuscitate'' order.
- 遗愿吗  - 对
- A living will? - Right.
你可以帮我吗
You can help me with that?
当然可以
Sure. Sure.
我让你生气了吗
Am I upsetting you?
没有
No.
对不起
Sorry.
你看上去有
You seem to have...
你有经历过跟这个一样的事情吗
You've been through something like this?
抱歉
Sorry.
不用管我
Oh, don't worry about me.
我是个辅导员  我就应该做这个
I'm a counselor. That's what I do.
今天早上  你来见我的时候
This morning, when you came to see me,
我直接扔下你不管  非常不专业
what I did, walking out on you like that, was really unprofessional.
没事
lt's okay.
不  我把自己的事情都告诉你了  我很抱歉
No. I put myself in front of you, and I'm---I'm sorry.
不  没事
No, it's okay.
等你帮完我这个忙  我来帮你
After you help me, I'm going to help you.
好的
Okay.
相信我  我会帮你的
Believe me, I am going to help you.
这周三  会有一位缅因州律所的诉讼监护人来访
On Wednesday, there'll be a visiting guardian ad litem from a clinic in Maine
想要跟着其中的某位律师  我想你再适合不过了
who wants to shadow one of the lawyers, and I thought you'd be the best choice.
当然
Sure.
额  当然  还有其他事吗
Uh, sure. Anything else?
有  你看到了  我这里出了点状况
Yeah, l, uh, have a little situation here, as you can see.
- 我注意到了  - 我反正不会走
- I've noticed. - I ain't leaving.
好极了
Great.
阿尔文  尼克撂挑子了  所以我在想
Alvin, Nick dropped the ball, so I'm just wondering
今天你能不能替我参加下午的股东大会
if you could cover for me in this afternoon's general meeting.
可以
Yeah.
好吧  我跟诉讼监护人那边安排过了
Okay. So, I arranged it with the guardian ad litem,
我们四点都能赶去那边
and we can all be there at 4.
好吧
Okay, then.
苏珊娜
Suzanne.
你知道我跟尼克同居了
You knew I was living with him.
嗯
Yeah.
你知不知道我怀孕了
Did you know that I was pregnant?
什么
What?
你知不知道尼克正在缓刑期
Did you know that Nick's on probation?
如果他被抓到嗑药或者酗酒的话  他有可能会被关进监狱的
That if he gets caught with drugs or drinking that he will go to jail?
- 不知道  - 你不知道吗
- No. - No?
那好  下次你见到他的时候请你告诉他
Okay. Well, you just please tell him the next time you see him
他已经造成了很多伤害
that he's done enough harm.
我不想再收拾他的烂摊子了  请一定转告他
And I'm tired of cleaning up his messes. You can just tell him that.
你跟他讲  让他4点一定要感到法院  否则我就给他的缓刑官打电话了
And you tell him to show up at the court at 4:OO or I will call his probation officer.
伯顿  他不在家
Burton, he's not home.
好吧
Okay.
我问过他的秘书了  也问过格雷琴  没人知道他去哪儿了
I spoke to his secretary and to Gretchen, and no one knows where he is.
该死
Damn.
Damn it!
放桌上吧
Just, uh, put them on the table.
听着  我想我可以在几个小时内汇总一下意见书
Look, I think I can pull together an opinion Ietter in a couple of hours.
这是合并需要的所有的文件  章程  宪章  诉讼  所有的文件
This is everything from the merger: bylaws, charter, lawsuits, everything.
给我几个小时  我来看一下  好吗
So give me a couple of hours to go through this, okay?
你可以在几小时内写一份意见信吗
You can draft an opinion letter in a couple of hours, huh?
我是个很棒的律师  伯顿  我看可以的
I'm a pretty good lawyer, Burton. I think I can handle it.
好吧
Okay.
给
Here you are.
看起来不错
Looks good.
你吃吧
You can eat.
你不吃吗
You're not hungry?
所以  遗嘱的事情
So, a living will.
是的
Right.
遗嘱里会写你希望正常自然地死亡
A living will says that you desire to die a natural death,
并且不希望用医疗设备或者急救措施来维持生命
and you don't want to be kept alive by medical treatment or heroic measures.
是的
That's what I want.
好吧  所以
Right. So...
这份声明写着你心智健全
This basically states that you are of sound mind
且是自愿提出这个声明的
and that you are voluntarily making this declaration.
是的
Okay.
你示意主治医生不再维持生命
That you direct the attending physician to withhold or withdraw life support.
是的
Okay.
那么  还有几个具体的问题
Then there are specific questions.
尽管问吧
Fire away.
你想不想进行心脏复苏
Do you want cardio-pulmonary resuscitation?
不想
No.
你想不想机械设备来维持呼吸
Do you want mechanical respiration?
不想
No.
还有哪些  你说
Just do the whole list, okay?
管饲  输血  手术  透析  抗生素
Tube feeding, blood transfusions, surgery, dialysis, antibiotics.
不要  不要  不要  都写不要
No. No. No to all that.
- 你想要捐赠器官吗  - 如果我的器官还能用的话
- Do you wish to donate any organs? - If they're useful.
- 嗨  妈妈  - 嗨  亲爱的
- Hey, Mom. - Hi, sweetheart.
我有好多作业
I have a lot of homework.
他很认真
He's so serious.
不看电视  也没有几个朋友  每天一回来就做作业
No TV. Not many friends. Just does his school work.
每门成绩都是A
Straight As.
其他妈妈都很羡慕我  都希望能有这样的孩子
The other moms, they wish their kid was just like mine,
但是  我不想这样  我宁愿他考个C  能时不时笑一笑
but, I don't know, I just wish he'd get a C and smile once in awhile.
是啊
Right.
我的小男子汉
My little man.
你好  亨德里克斯小姐  你在这边坐得还舒服吗
Hi, Miss Hendricks. How's your sit-in going?
需不需要去趟洗手间
Need to use the bathroom?
露露  我不是有意
Lulu, uh, I don't mean to...
今天有人见过尼克吗
Has anybody actually spoken to Nick today?
没有
No.
我们要不要担心
Should we be concerned?
不
No.
好吧
Okay.
你好  我是路易莎·阿切尔
Louisa Archer.
好的
Okay.
好的  谢谢你  罗斯玛丽  谢谢
All right, thank you, Rosemarie. Thank you.
刚才是你的缓刑官打来的
That was your probation officer.
他现在要在法院见我们
She's gonna meet us at the courthouse right now.
关键是你的手要很放松
lt's important to keep your hand really relaxed.
要很灵活
You gotta be limber.
- 嗨  露露  - 嗨 伯顿
- Hey, Lulu. - Hi, Burton.
- 我在找尼克  - 我也是
- I'm looking for Nick. - Me, too.
有没有给他家里打电话
Have you tried calling him at home?
有  打过了  我甚至叫杰克去他家看过了  但是
Yeah, I did. Even had Jake go over there but, uh...
那么  他有可能
Well, he's probably--
我觉得我们都知道他去干嘛了
I think we both know
what he's probably doing.
- 嗨  阿尔文  - 嗨  伯顿
- Hey, Alvin. - Hey, Burton.
你介意我去尼克的办公室看看吗  我在找一本法律意见书
Do you mind if I check out Nick's office? I'm looking for a legal opinion.
- 不介意  进去吧  - 谢谢
- No, go right ahead. - Thanks.
关于你儿子的监护权
As for the custody of your son...
怎么了
Right?
- 不会很容易  - 好吧
- It's not gonna be easy. - Okay.
按照宾夕法尼亚州的关于亲生父母的法律规定
Presumption in Pennsylvania is for the biological parent.
嗯
Right.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
你的前夫有权决定孩子去哪里
Your ex-husband has the legal right to contest the placement.
但是  还是有其他办法的吧
But there is a way?
是的  有个规定叫备用监护人法案
Yes, there's something called the Standby Guardian Act.
你真的  你真的很在行
You're really... You're so good at this.
你真的很聪明
You're really smart.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以  备用监护人法案
So, the Standby Guardian Act.
这个法案允许身患绝症的父母做出监护权的决定
It allows a terminally ill parent to commence a custody action
断定另一位家长无法照顾这个孩子
that alleges that the other parent is unable to care for their child.
好的
Okay.
你可以试着指定一个新的监护人
You could try to designate a new guardian.
但是我猜你不会赢
My guess is you will lose.
是啊
Right.
你跟我说他爸爸并没有虐待或者冷落孩子
From what you've told me of your son's father, he's not abusive or neglectful.
他不是一个好爸爸  他不爱孩子
Well, he's not a good father. He's not loving.
法律上没有关于爱的规定
Legally ''loving'' is not a requirement.
是啊  是的
Right. Right.
你有没有考虑问下你的儿子他想怎么做
Have you considered asking your son what he wants to do?
他还只是个孩子
Oh, he's just a boy.
不  我需要给他制定一个切实可行的计划
No. I need to come up with a solid plan for him.
给他制定切实可行的计划吗
A solid plan for him?
是啊
Exactly.
你需要问问他  他想做什么
You need to ask him what he wants to do.
他还只是个孩子
He's just a boy.
我能不能用下洗手间
ls there a bathroom I might use?
楼上  走廊的尽头
Upstairs, end of the hall.
- 嗨  杰瑞  - 嗨  阿尔文
- Hi, Jerry. - Alvin.
- 你认识尼克·法林吗  - 认识
- You know Nick Fallin? - Sure.
- 今天有见到他吗  - 没有
- Seen him around today? - Nah.
如果今天见到他  能不能打电话通知我一声
Oh, uh, if you see him, would you give me a call?
- 当然  - 谢谢
- Sure. - Thanks.
有消息了吗
Any word yet?
还没有
Uh, no.
好吧  我必须进去了  告诉客户们事情的真相
Well, I'm gonna have to go in there and... tell the clients.
我快好了
I'm--I'm almost finished.
你不可能分析出风险和负债的
You couldn't have analyzed the risks and liabilities.
已经足够了
lt's good enough.
但是  我不能
Well, I can't go in--
我的意思是  如果你弄错了  我们会被起诉
I mean, if you're wrong, we get sued.
伯顿  如果不去  我们还是会被起诉的
Burton, we're gonna get sued either way.
不  这不是我的办事风格
Nah, I don't do business like this.
什么  相信我伯顿  这也不是我的办事风格
What? Believe me, Burton, I don't do business like this.
我的意思是  我现在只是在弥补尼克的
I mean, I'm just trying to cover Nick--
你有没有进他的房子
Did you go inside the house?
没有
No.
杰克
Jake!
听着  去他的房子  如果需要撬开
Look, go back over there, and if you have to break--
花盆下面有一把钥匙
There's a key underneath the planter.
去办公室把那封意见信找出来
Go inside the house and find the damn letter!
这样做会更好
It would be better this way.
好个屁
Like hell it would.
我只是希望他待在爱他的人的身边
I just want him to be around someone who loves him.
你听听你自己的话  你在说什么
What are you saying? Listen to yourself.
你一直醉心工作  而且你很容易愤怒
You work all the time and you're so angry.
安妮  拜托
Anne, please.
我希望孩子跟我在一起  他是我的儿子
This is what I want. He is my child.
我是不会放弃他的  我不会把他送给别人的
I will never, never give him up, never give him away.
你明白吗
You understand that?
你没有在听我说话  你没有在听
You are not hearing me. You're not listening.
我们得为他做出最好的选择
We have got to do what is best for him.
他最需要的是关心和爱  不是愤怒
And what is best for him is attention and love, not anger.
他还只是个孩子
He's just a little boy.
我们谈崩了
That didn't go very well.
他不同意
He won't agree to it.
是吗
Right.
我还是希望走法律的途径
I still want to take this to court.
是吗
You do?
至少
At least...
我希望我的儿子知道  妈妈真的努力做到最好了
I want my son to know, at least, that I tried to do what I felt was best.
就是这本
This is it.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
好吧
All right.
我前夫很有权势
My ex-husband is a powerful guy.
好的
Okay.
你不懂  他真的很有权势
No. I mean, he's a powerful guy.
他是个律师  他这个人心狠手辣
He's a lawyer, and he's very tough.
我可以解决
Well, I can handle myself.
会有很多人跟他一起来
He'll bring a lot of people with him.
他会表现得很友好  他是他会嘲弄也会很傲慢
He'll act kindly, but he'll be derisive and condescending.
好的
Okay.
他会把我说成另外一个人
He'll make me out to be someone I'm not.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他肯定会提到我一直和
He might bring up the fact that I've struggled with--
和什么
With what?
药物和酒精作斗争的事
Pills. Alcohol.
他可能会提到
He might bring that up.
这是不相关的事  法官只会在乎
lt's irrelevant. The judge is only concerned
你的妹妹和你的前夫
with your sister and your ex-husband.
对  是的
Right. Right.
安妮  抱歉  路上堵  停车又花了点时间
Anne! I'm so sorry. Tramic and parking.
嗨  尼克
Oh, hi, Nick.
丽兹阿姨
Aunt Liz?
安妮  听我说  我觉得我做不到
Anne, listen, I don't think I can do this.
- 丽兹  - 我爱你的儿子  我真的爱他
- Liz. - I love your son. I really do.
但是我觉得现在不是时候
But I don't think now's the time to do this.
- 你之前答应我了  - 我确实说了
- You said that you would. - I did.
因为我觉得你前夫是
Because I think your husband is...
我同意你之前说的很多事情  但是  安妮
I agree with a lot of the things you say but, Anne,
我觉得你这么做是为了报复他
I think you're doing this to get back at him,
不是因为你认为这样是为了你儿子好
not because you think that this is best for your son.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧
Okay.
所以我儿子要跟着他爸爸了
So, he goes to live with his dad.
是的
Right.
那我回去帮他收拾行李吧
Well, I better go get him packed.
什么
What?
- 我希望他今晚就走  - 为什么
- I want him to go tonight. - Why?
因为我不想让他跟我一起经历这些
Because I don't want him to go through this with me.
他甚至还不知道这件事
He doesn't even know yet.
是啊
Right.
但是  他也得现在就走了  早点去适应那边
Well, he'll just have to go now and get used to where he'll be.
安妮  他还不知道
Anne, he doesn't know.
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your help.
但是我必须得这么做
But this is the way it's gotta be.
法林先生呢
Where's Mr. Fallin?
我代替他出庭  法官大人
I'm filling in for him, Your Honor.
好吧
All right.
亨德里克斯小姐
Miss Hendricks.
我看到你断绝了和你前男友的往来
I see you've stopped all contact with your former boyfriend,
修完了父母育儿课程  找到了一份工作
have completed your parenting classes, have a job.
家庭调查的结果也很不错
Home study looks good.
谢谢
Thank you.
但是我没有看到你的
I don't, however, see a certificate of completion
戒毒康复的证书
for your drug rehabilitation program.
我拿到了  我完成了
I took it. I finished it.
是  但是我没有看到
Yes, but I don't see proof of that.
阿切尔小姐
Miss Archer?
我恐怕  法官大人  我没有
Um, I'm afraid, Your Honor, I don't--
我三天前就把证书给了那个该死的律师
I gave it to that damn lawyer! Three days ago!
我在周五给了他
I gave it to him on Friday!
不好意思  亨德里克斯小姐  我必须看到一张签过字的表格
I'm sorry, Miss Hendricks, but I need to see a signed form before me.
法官大人  我宝贝女儿已经在那个烂地方住了快半年了
Judge, my baby girl has been living in a crappy hellhole for almost six months--
- 阿切尔女士  - 我只想让她跟我回家啊
- Miss Archer. - And I just want to get her home to me!
- 请你坐下  - 阿切尔小姐  管管你的当事人
- You need to sit down! - Miss Archer, your client!
阿切尔小姐
Miss Archer!
我要看到证书
Bring me the form.
你根本不懂你的孩子被夺走是一种什么样的感觉
You don't understand what it's like to have your baby taken from you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
本来就是今天的
It was supposed to be today.
我把家里布置得好好的  我的朋友
I had the house all done up and my friends...
本来就是今天的
It was supposed to be today.
怎么了
What?
我对我所做的感到抱歉
I'm sorry...what I did.
我只是
I just...
这不是我三言两句就能解决的事情
lt's not really something I can make go away with words, so...
我只是对他又感觉
I just really felt something for him.
很强烈的感觉
I felt a lot.
我从来过这样的感受  从来没有
That doesn't happen for me, that doesn't.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
- 拿到了  - 太好了
- I got it. - Great.
- 你在哪儿找到的  - 它就在厨房的柜台上
- Where'd you find it? - It was on the counter in the kitchen.
- 尼古拉斯在吗  - 他不在  但是
- Was Nicholas there? - No. No, he wasn't, but--
我是说  看上去挺好的  所以
I mean, it all looked good, so...
好的
Okay.
好吧  我们把这事做完吧
Well, let's get this thing done.
对
Yeah.
好吧  很抱歉耽误大家这么长时间  大家都坐吧
All right. Sorry for the delay. Why don't you have a seat?
我不想让他记着我病恹恹  日渐消瘦的样子
I don't want him to remember me sick, wasting away.
你不能就这样把他赶出去吧
You can't just kick him out.
- 他不应该这样面对这件事  - 他必须这样
- He shouldn't have to face this. - He'll want to.
所以你就把他送去学校
So you're just gonna drive off to the school
然后告诉他你不能再陪伴他了吗
and tell him that he can't be around you anymore?
- 这样对大家都好  - 都好吗
- It's for the best. - For the best?
- 是的  - 安妮  问问他他想要什么吧
- Yes. - Anne, just ask him what he wants.
- 他不知道  - 他知道
- He doesn't know. - He does!
- 不  他不知道  - 他想跟你在一起
- No, he doesn't! - He wants to stay with you!
他想知道  他有帮助你
He wants to know that he's helped you!
他不应该面对这一切  他不是那种孩子
He shouldn't have to face this. He is not that kind of child.
他已经和他爸爸很生疏了
He's already so removed.
如果我让他继续待在这里  情况会更糟糕的
lf I let him stay, it'll only make him worse.
事实不是你想的那样的
You don't know that!
你没有办法知道某天他一觉醒来躺在他爸爸的家里是什么样
You don't know what it's like for him to suddenly wake up in his father's house
直到你卧床不起  他才能来看你
and to not see you again until you're too sick to object to his being there!
他应该习惯跟他爸爸待在一起
He should get used to being with his father.
他还有那么长时间跟他爸爸在一起  但是陪你的时间只有几个月了
He has the rest of his life for that. He only has a few months left with you.
安妮  我很抱歉好吗
Anne. Anne, I'm sorry, okay?
能不能听我说
Will you please listen to me?
安妮  求你了
Anne, please.
让他跟你待在一起吧  直到他准备好了
Just let him stay with you until he's ready to go.
为什么我要这么做
Why would I do that?
因为他会变的
Because he'll change.
他会变成一个
He'll end up...
变成什么  尼克
He'll end up what, Nick?
我这是为了他好
lt's for his own good.
不要走
Don't go.
求你了  求你了  求你了  不要走
Please. Please. Please, don't go.
我会帮你的  尼克
I'll still help you, Nick.
求你了  求你了  别走
Please. Please don't go.
我跟你说了  我会帮你的
I'll help you, like I said I would.
别走
Don't go.
尼克
Nick!
醒醒  尼克
Nick! Nick!
没事的
lt's okay.
尼克  尼克  醒醒   没事了
Nick! Nick! It's all right!
我吃了美人
I took beautiful.
尼克  你吃了什么  尼克  尼克
Nick, what'd you take? Nick! Nick!
我们带你出去  我们会照顾好你的
We're gonna get you outta here. We'll take care of this.
走吧  尼克  我们走
Come on, Nick. Come on!
好吧  我们走
All right. Come on.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
怎么样了
How you doing?
蓝色梦幻是吧
Blue Mystic, huh?
是的
Yeah.
嗑太多了吧
Too much of a good thing?
是的
Something like that.
他们为你做了什么
What'd they do for you?
你知道的  他们就给了我一些
You know, they just gave me some...
托住我的头  聊了聊
Held my hand, talked me down.
感谢他们没有报警
Nice of them not to call the police.
是啊
Yeah.
我代理这家医院
Well, I do represent the hospital.
是啊  我都忘了
Right. I forgot about that.
至少以前有
At least I used to.
我打电话告诉你爸了
I called your father.
也跟露露说了
And I spoke to Lulu.
告诉他们不要过来了  我送你回家
Told them not to come down here, that I'd take you home.
谢谢
Thank you.
你以后慢慢谢
Well, we'll see about that.
你嗑的那种药  蓝色梦幻
That drug you took, Blue Mystic.
- 是的  - 为什么
- Right. - Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
为什么是这种药
Why that drug?
有个人  他告诉我
This guy, he, uh... he told me...
他说这个药嗑了之后感觉无与伦比
He said it was incredible.
哦
Yeah.
确实是这样  无与伦比
And it was. Incredible.
但是只维持了一段时间
It was...for a while.
致幻剂  我记得那种感觉
Hallucinogens. I remember.
无与伦比
lncredible.
我没事了  阿尔文  谢谢你  你可以回家了
I'm fine, Alvin. Thank you. You can go home.
嗯  我知道
Yeah, I know.
现在已经4点了  我也很累了
lt's 4 in the morning, and I'm pretty tired.
是  肯定很累了
Right. I'm sure.
嗯
Yeah.
所以  你应该
So, uh, you should...
回家了吧
Go?
是啊
Right.
你要不要喝杯茶
Would you like some tea?
不用
No.
你呢
You?
我要
Yeah.
如果你不介意的话
lf you wouldn't mind.
嗨
Hey.
外面真的太冷了
Cold as hell out there.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
所以
So...
我们都坐吧  坐下谈一谈
why don't we sit down and have a little talk.
我要做什么
What do I do?
坐在那边  告诉他们你的名字
Go over there and give them your name.
好吗
Okay?
好吧
All right.
嗨  我叫尼克·法林
Hi, uh, my name is Nick Fallin.
我需要跟人谈一谈
I wanted to talk to someone.
好的  我已经知道你的基本信息了
Okay, I've got all your basic information.
好的
Okay.
我们有几个选择
We've got a few options here.
嗯
Right.
我不觉得我们需要承认你要去戒毒诊所
I don't think we need to admit you for detox.
不需要
No.
我感觉我们在接下来的一个月都需要门诊治疗
My feeling is we should start outpatient for the next 30 days.
好的
Right.
也就是每晚4个小时  每周五天
That's four hours a night, five days a week.
好的
Right.
你觉得你可以吗
You think you can handle that?
法林先生
Mr. Fallin?
可以
Yes.
好的
Good.
我们会帮你的  法林先生
We're gonna help you, Mr. Fallin.
好的
Okay.
我们会尽全力帮你
We will give you all the help you need.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在轮到你选择了  尼克
lt's your turn, Nick.
如果你准备好了  轮到你选择了
lf you're ready, it's your turn.
尼克
Nick.
安妮塔·亨德里克斯需要你跟她去法庭
Anita Hendricks needs you to take her to court.
对
Right.
她说她把戒毒康复的证书给你了
And she said that she gave you her certificate for her drug rehab.
确实给我了  在我的办公室
She did. It's in my office.
你知道吗  她非常生气
Well, you know, she's pretty angry,
所以也许你应该把证书给我  让我
so maybe you could just give it to me and I'll--
不用  她是我的客户
No, she's my client.
- 我知道  但是也许我可以  - 她是我的客户
- I know, but maybe I could just-- - She's my client.
好吧  亨德里克斯小姐  我知道我们今天中午12点要去法庭
Okay, Miss Hendricks, I understand we have a 12:OO today.
可不是吗
Damn straight.
好的  进我办公室吧  我们把文件准备好
Well, if you step into my office, we can get that form ready.
你没有什么话跟我说吗
Don't you got something to say to me?
你说得对  我有话说
You're right, I do. Um...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧
Well?
All right, then.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177